A Film by EDWARD YANG
Produced by YU WEI-YEN,
JAN HUNG-TZE, and EDWARD YANG
My son's always done well in
Chinese literature. SUMMER 1959
He couldn't have scored just 50.
He got close to 100
in everything else.
There must be some mistake.
Mr. Wang is our friend as well.
He understands our procedure.
We'll double-check
your son's scores.
I'm afraid I can't show you
the exam papers.
It's against our regulations.
You idiot!
Hot tea in this weather?
I promise
to double-check his scores.
If the examination board
made any mistakes,
we'll make
any necessary adjustments.
You can trust me.
You know, night school
at Jianguo High isn't bad.
LISA YANG, CHANG CHEN
CHANG KUO-CHU, ELAINE JIN
Script And Dialogue by EDWARD YANG,
YAN HONG-YA ALEX YANG, LAI MING-TANG
Cinematography by
CHANG HUI-KUNG, Ll LONG-YU
Sound by
TU DUU-CHIH
Edited by BOWEN CHEN
Production Manager WU ZHUANG
Planned by
TAN YUN-SHENG
Presented by CHENG SUl-JE, LIN
HSIN-NAN STAN LAI, EDWARD YANG
Executive Producers
JAN HUNG-TZE, JIANG FENG-CHYI
Produced by
YU WEI-YEN
Directed by EDWARD YANG
Yeh Ming-shew. ..
Wang LiaflQ'Yu...
Chang Guang-hsi...
Lin Deng-fei...
The preceding have qualified
for the Education Department
at the National Political
Science University.
Next, for the Political Science
Department
at National Political
Science University,
the following
28 students have qualified:
Hsu Hsin-Iiang, Wang Shi-yeh...
Millions of mainland Chinese
fled to Taiwan in 1949
with the Nationalist government
after its defeat in the civil war
by the Chinese Communists.
Their children were brought up
in an uneasy atmosphere
created by their parents'
uncertainty about the future.
Many formed street gangs
to search for an identity
and to strengthen
their sense of security.
SEPTEMBER 1960
Why this color?
Why worry about the color?
It's a black-and-white film!
How can I wear
such an awful color?
I told you to change, so change!
There's no dressing room.
I told you to change,
not to go nude!
What are you so upset for?
Move!
Didn't we agree on the dress?
Now you're changing things
on the spot!
Listen, everyone:
This is our last shot.
Let's get it over with!
Someone's up there!
Kid, what are you doing up there?
You're not getting away,
you little brat!
Think you can run away?
You should be in school.
What are you doing here?
What's your name?
Night school? What class?
I have ways to make you talk!
8-6-O-8-9.
Who's that? Don't run off!
Stay where you are!
Fucking kids! I'll kill you!
Smooch, smooch!
Have a kiss! Score a Miss!
Hanky-panky time!
Attention.
Salute.
Be seated.
Hey, Airplane!
Fly over here!
Where'd you get the flashlight?
Xiao Si'r snatched it
from the film studio.
Shut up, Underpants!
Stop asking about the test!
Panty, panty, flimsy and fancy!
If you get sweaty,
use it as a hanky.
Get one for your mommy!
Hush up. It's Red Bean.
Shine it on her.
Go on!
How's it work?
What are you little brats up to?
- I bet you they're red!
- Bullshit!
- Wanna bet?
- How much?
- Ten bucks.
- No, one.
- One buck?
- You call that a bet?
Shit, what a cheapskate!
You're too cheap to bet with.
You never pay up.
- Looks like somethings up.
- Must be something bad.
It's none of your damn business.
There's a fight.
Sly's cornered at the grade school.
Si'r, let me have that.
- Okay.
- Sex Bomb, we need your help.
- No problem.
- I'm not going.
- Who asked you?
Forget about him.
Let's go.
- He'll hit the porn stand again.
- Porn freak!
Hold it!
Sly, you okay?
Shit!
What took you so long?
Can't even take care
of our own turf!
Are we giving it up or what?
Got a smoke on you?
Hey, Deuce.
Shit! How did this happen?
They got me alone, that's all.
I held them off
by myself till now.
You try that next time.
I'm not blaming you.
But what are you
doing here so late?
None of your business.
How could we let the 217 gang
mess with our turf?
I tell you,
everyone's out to get us.
If it weren't the 217 boys,
it'd be others.
If your brother doesn't
come back soon, we're through.
- Honey's not here. I am.
- You are!
Please don't beat me up!
I'm sorry!
Don't beat me up!
I was just tagging along.
I'm not one of them.
We're not enemies!
So you two want to go big time?
This kid's too noisy.
Shut him up.
Don't hit me!
Watch closely.
Get a good look.
We don't need
chickenshit cowards.
Get up.
Get up!
Go back
and tell your big brother!
Never fuck
with the Little Park boys!
Why are you switching
the lights on and off?
My eyes go blurry.
I don't know why.
Get to bed earlier
and you'll be okay.
Why are you home so late?
We all stayed afterwards
to talk about the test.
It won't work!
I can't button it!
Make it work for now.
The bus is coming.
Lao Er, why aren't you up?
Do I have to drag you
out of bed every day?
Mom, it fell off!
There's no time to sew it on.
Use a pin for now.
What's wrong?
Outgrew your clothes again?
Mom, I can't find a pin!
- I'm o“.
- Where are you going this early?
- We Saturday.
- It's too early even for Saturday.
It's our class's turn
at the weekly meeting.
- No shoes in the house!
- I need my compass!
- Wow! Just out of the tub!
- What do they teach you!
You're like Americans,
bathing in the morning.
- It's none of your business!
- Let's go.
Good-bye.
I'll be available
every Saturday afternoon
at the infirmary.
I owe so much to my alma mater
and to Principal He
for what I've achieved today.
I honestly feel
I don't deserve this recognition.
I feel it's my duty to volunteer
to serve in your clinic.
Thank you.
Student 8-6-0-8-9!
Report to the conduct office
at once!
Those of you
who like baseball, listen up.
A day school student
hurt Mr. Chen yesterday
with a baseball bat.
Did you hear about it?
Starting today,
all baseball bats
must be registered.
All unregistered bats
will be confiscated.
You hear me?
It was him! I'm positive!
I didn't take your flashlight.
Where's the other boy?
Who's the other boy?
We didn't mean any harm.
He didn't take it, I swear.
- Were you with him yesterday?
- Yes.
Get over there!
- Was it you who broke my window?
- No.
What's going on?
Zhang Zhen was hanging
around the film studio.
Now somethings missing.
These students get
craftier every year.
But your film studio
is right next door.
No, thanks.
I can't solve
this problem for you.
Of course not.
A student cracked
a teacher's skull
with one of those recently.
It's a real problem!
You'd better come down
hard on them.
Our principal insists
on developing their free spirits.
Our school gate's never locked.
You better lock your gates tight.
You leave yours open,
and we'll leave ours open.
We can visit each other!
Why are you spreading
rumors about me?
What did I say?
You said I was with a girl
that night at the school.
You didn't see a thing,
understand?
- That's my seat.
- Take mine in the back.
Salute.
Let me copy off you.
Just see what happens
if you don't.
- Did you answer No. 4?
- Forget it. Let's play ball.
Okay.
FUCK you!
Don't give me that look.
Wouldn't let me copy, huh?
Keep staring, tough guy.
Just try it. I dare you.
Hello, sir.
We're just playing around.
You boys enjoy
coming to my office?
If so,
I'm at your service anytime.
He's not your regular bookworm.
If you lock horns,
he doesn't fuck around.
What about my bat?
I'll get you another one.
I just bought that one.
Seventy bucks!
Please deliver this, Uncle Fat.
You've got men in the family.
They can pick it up!
Si?!
Stop drinking, will you?
You'd better go.
What happened to your face?
I hurt it playing baseball.
You hurt it playing baseball?
Let's not buy from Uncle Fat
on credit anymore.
He's been real mean lately.
I have no idea why.
He's jealous of you
going to the university.
His daughter failed
the exam again this year.
That music
from the fruit stand again!
It's louder every day.
Eight years of war
with the Japanese.
Now we live in a Japanese house
and listen to Japanese music.
Don't forget we're invited
to Wang's for dinner Sunday.
Do I have to go?
Won't it be all grown-ups?
- Why'd you eat so little?
- There'll be lots of children.
I'm full.
Shall we bring a present?
Sure.
“The score with Sly
will be settled by this day.”
Here, 70 bucks.
All right!
Where'd you get it?
Don't ask too many questions.
Kennedy's experience
in foreign affairs
is very limited.
Faced with the world's
communist community,
the American public
won't entrust the presidency
to a young,
inexperienced fellow like him.
Thomas, get in the back.
Little girl,
stand behind your mother.
Wan-wan, don't hide in back.
You're always so shy.
Wang, you have us over every time
you return from an official trip.
“Official trip”!
I go for the fun of it.
America's incredible.
The skyscrapers -
- Are you kidding?
- Absolutely not!
They've got skyscrapers,
and Disneyland!
Mickey Mouse.
A great place for kids.
They gave me a tour
of an atomic bomb factory.
If I were an expert,
I'd have learned to make
my own A-bomb.
Then I could blow
the Communists to hell.
Okay, time for the picture.
Everyone look this way.
Don't say anything
until it's officially announced.
Thank you.
This is a nice surprise.
Don't mention it.
We're such old friends.
But there's something
I must remind you of.
It's been 12 years
since we came here
from Shanghai.
It's unlikely
we'll ever make it back.
While there's still time,
we should make
some long-term plans.
Your old Shanghai
intellectual mentality -
get rid of it.
Watch your temper.
You have to learn to be flexible.
On the surface,
I'm helping you
get this promotion.
Actually, you'll be helping me
in the future.
We're classmates.
Old friends.
Like in a gang.
Understand?
Getting Si'r transferred
back to day school
is no problem
with my current connections.
Thanks.
The night school's awful.
I worry about him turning bad.
What are you doing?
Get lost.
- You picked a good spot to watch.
- What?
Out of the way!
Mom, I'm bored.
Let's go home.
Soon, soon.
It's still like new.
I almost never use it.
I rarely have the occasion
to wear such a nice watch.
How time flies.
When I gave you that watch...
Why did you mention Professor Hsia
in front of Mrs. Hsia?
I didn't.
She saw my watch.
Why did Professor Hsia
go back to Shanghai alone?
Bringing more relatives over
must have been an excuse.
Mrs. Hsia's lived
like a widow ever since.
What was Wang
talking to you about?
Oh, nothing.
He can help get Si'r
transferred to day school.
There shouldn't be any problem.
What about
my teaching certificate?
You don't seem too concerned
about my problems.
Luckily my letter of employment
came early this year.
Every year I go
through the same stress.
You know what I mean.
Whose fault is that?
I told you to bring your official papers
when we left Shanghai.
I did. I put them
in the candy tin that we brought.
Don't read on the bus.
You'll ruin your eyes.
Those night classes
must be hurting Si'r's eyes.
They claim the free shots
at school will help.
I hope it will save us
from having to buy him glasses.
He has a secret to tell you.
What secret?
Tell her.
She'll give you a freebie.
I come here often
because you're so pretty.
I'll take this.
- You have to pay! Give it back!
- I have no money.
- Then give it back.
No.
No?
Don't unwrap it!
Don't you unwrap it!
Give it back!
They're red!
- You owe me 10 bucks!
- No, one!
Tiger, you're cheating!
Don't touch that!
One at a time.
Don't you know how to line up?
Wang Chun-ming.
Four times a day.
Come back if it doesn't help.
A stomachache?
You're sure?
You're not trying to fool me?
- No.
You can't get sent home
that easily.
Come to my clinic tomorrow
for another treatment.
Miss Ling.
Can you walk by yourself?
- I think so.
Give it a try.
Let's do this. You there.
Please help her back
to her classroom.
It's okay.
I can walk by myself.
You can go back to class.
I'm fine.
Our military adviser.
- A pack of New Paradise.
- Three fifty.
- You're new here.
- That's right.
- Where are you from?
- Taichung.
He caught me cutting class once.
I used to live near Taichung,
at the CCK air base.
It reminds me of Wuhan,
on the mainland.
We can't stay here forever.
You can't keep me
waiting here forever.
The boss is taking me
to Hong Kong next month.
You want anything
from Hong Kong?
Let me think about it.
I 'II tell you tonight.
Time for makeup.
Oh, I can't make it
tomorrow evening.
Field Marshal Wong
is taking me to dinner.
We made the date yesterday...
uh, last month.
If you want to quit, tell the boss
and save us both the trouble!
I didn't say that.
Stop looking for excuses.
Me look for excuses?
You're the one
looking for excuses!
Me look for excuses?
And why all the heavy makeup?
It doesn't show my finest features.
What features?
Besides the boss liking you,
what else have you got?
There's no talking to you!
Did I say anything
about your script?
Where'd you copy it from?
I'm telling the boss.
To hell with you!
Get the hell out!
Who's the director here,
you or me?
Bitching about too much makeup!
What the hell!
Look in the mirror!
That face needs
all the makeup it can get!
Young lady.
What grade are you in?
Eighth.
Assistant!
This young girl isn't bad.
What do you think?
Get her address.
The role calls for a teenager.
You're pushing 40,
and you have the nerve to bitch?
Would you be interested
in a screen test?
So you live by Little Park too?
Lots of my classmates
live there.
You gonna do the screen test?
My boyfriend will be angry
if he finds out.
You going back to class?
Where else can we go?
How do you know about this place?
I used to live near here.
I don 7 see any houses.
If I were a guy,
I'd love to be in the army.
Why are you guys
all afraid of the army?
We're afraid of that.
Oh, look. A couple.
Dating one of our girls, eh?
It'll cost you, you hear?
- Ignore him.
- Ignore me?
He wouldn't dare!
You hiding your watch or what?
I don't have one.
Aren't you the soft-spoken one!
Want me to search you?
Lousy pen.
Dating a girl
without the dough -
No, don't! Let's go!
Hurry! Let's go, Si?!
Get on.
I'll give you a ride.
It's out of your way.
There's a bus up ahead.
I'm heading for Little Park too!
Don't you want to win back
what you lost?
You've got some attitude!
I'll keep it myself.
Leave me alone!
Threads, where you been?
It's so dark in here.
How about turning on some lights?
You owe 2,140.
Wanna pay up now
or try to win it back?
Win it back, of course.
Crazy, how about letting him
have a shot?
That bookworm?
Wow, from Jianguo High!
Scared you'll lose?
Rack 'em up.
That's it.
Let him learn from experience.
Lao Er, let's do it.
- Wait a minute.
Lao Er? “Prick”?
Haven't you got one already?
This one's for you.
Don't let him bother you.
Baldy, this kid's called Prick.
What's wrong?
- Nothing.
Nothing?
You look like shit.
What have you been up to lately?
Not much.
Things have been tough.
Ihear
you're putting on a concert.
There's no money in that.
Not like your racket here.
Got something going
with those rock and roll boys again?
That's about all
they've got going.
Not those Little Park boys again!
Five ball, side pocket.
Seven ball, corner pocket.
Four ball, corner pocket.
What a fluke!
The kid's got all the luck!
Damn! Set 'em up.
Come on, set 'em up.
You guys are going easy on us.
Take your time.
We'll win it all back.
Keep your cool.
Take your time.
Take it easy.
Plenty of time.
Two hundred a game.
Interesting... interesting.
Didn't you ditch class to go home?
Yeah, but I didn't go home.
Come help me with this.
Who the fuck you take me for?
Stay the hell out of my business!
My old man's in charge
of the auditorium.
We share the profits
from the concert.
Why give Threads such a big cut?
- Threads is here to help!
- Help how?
He's taking advantage
of our gang.
Let me tell you something.
I'm gonna tell him
he can't use the hall.
The question is:
Would you stop singing?
What the fuck are you saying?
Let me go!
Let him go. it's cool.
Fuck you, man!
What the fuck are you saying?
Jade, it's none
of your business! Get out!
Let me go!
You've gone too far this time!
Motherfucker!
Don't go inside.
You started it.
- Me?
You said you saw Jade
with Sly that night.
Now the shit's hit the fan.
- I didn't say it was Jade.
- Who else would it be?
My precious little baby!
I'll swallow you up in one bite!
Blind Man's jealous
of you already.
If Honey were here,
none of this
would have happened.
Threads wouldn't dare
underestimate us.
Now both Deuce and Sly
want to be boss.
Cat, you're on!
Now what?
Why did you say
I was with Sly that night?
I didn't say it was you.
I couldn't see clearly.
Wasn't it you?
Yeah... it was.
Sorry! I didn't mean it!
I thought no one was home!
Little thief! If anything's stolen,
we'll come looking for you!
Where's Si'r?
- I guess he's out.
What are you doing here?
Ask your big sister to transcribe
some lyrics for me, okay?
Sis, can you help him?
Transcribing lyrics again?
You want to sing American songs
when you don't know a word of English!
Don't be mad.
I didn't look on purpose.
I didn't see anything.
But I gotta say
that dress looks great!
I don't have a lot of time.
She fell for it.
Your sweet talk worked again.
Sis, I forgot my lunch box.
Mom says to reheat it for me.
Where's Mom?
Supervising an exam.
Wow, a new dress!
That's strange.
Did you plug it in?
Yeah.
Damn it.
It's not working.
What now?
I know.
Bring me your radio.
Wow, you copied this one!
- What are you doing?
- Nothing. Just fixing it.
- I'm going!
- Without your lunch?
Don't spend your pocket money
onjunkfood!
Make it last!
Will this work?
Nothing smaller?
Si'r, you boys want lunch?
- Not right now.
- I ate.
- Why isn't it working?
- It should be.
Sure you put it
back together right?
Don't be stupid.
I numbered everything.
You fucked it up.
Stay cool, man.
See?
Piece of shit.
I'll find you a new one.
Got any money?
When have I ever had money?
- And you?
- Trying to rip me off?
Come on.
Go inside and get some.
You see that?
What?
My old man's inside.
What a day, man.
Tiger.
What's the deal
with Ming's injured leg?
I heard it was from
playing basketball with you.
Come on.
Let's talk somewhere else.
Why can't we talk here?
If we talk here,
it won't look good for you.
Interesting.
Tell me what won't look good.
You should be clear
about whose girl Ming is.
- I am.
- Good.
If Honey found out,
he wouldn't be pleased.
My job is to make sure
he doesn't find out.
He won't find out.
He better not.
Keep that in mind.
Hey, I'm not done with you.
What's the big idea?
What are you doing?
This is between him and me.
You two are classmates.
Why all the fuss?
FUCK you!
- This is between him and me.
- And Ming!
Isn't he going out with Ming too?
Someone saw them
in a classroom that night.
Tell us what's wrong.
Tell us.
We want to know.
Go tell your Little Park gang.
I've known Honey for years.
I'll take all you sissies on
anytime!
Now get back to class.
Get back to class!
Mom, let me borrow
your earrings and watch.
Sure, but be extra careful
with the watch.
How come
there's only NT$800 left?
I paid our tab at Uncle Fat's
so he won't squawk
next time we buy on credit.
Wang got you a promotion
but not a raise in pay.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
What's with the radio?
What's going on?
I saw Si'r taking it apart
at lunchtime.
Damn it.
Stand up.
Where's your composition?
You're the only one
who didn't hand one in.
Excuse me.
This is Ma,
our new transfer student.
Let's welcome him.
As I was saying,
Chinese characters
reveal a great logic.
Foreign languages can't compare.
Twenty-six letters
mixed and matched - that's all.
Monotonous and tedious.
Take the character shan,
meaning “mountain.”
Spell it in English for me.
How tedious!
He's the guy who knifed someone
at Banqiao High.
Wang Mao, stand up.
You have something to add?
No.
Then what were you discussing?
Sir, what about “I”?
What do you mean,
what about you?
No, I mean from what you said,
what about the character for “I”?
Come up here.
Come up front.
You know
the character wo means "I".
- Yeah.
- Then write it.
You're fond of that word,
aren't you?
Write it a hundred times.
Go on!
You seem to enjoy it.
Keep writing!
That's two. Good.
Keep going.
Who's hissing?
Zhang Zhen, stand up.
Who hissed at me?
Speak up.
I don't know.
Then who were you looking at?
Who was it?
I didn't see anyone.
Fine.
If you won't say, it was you.
Stay standing.
Let's turn to page 33.
Xiao Si'r!
- You got any porn?
- Yes.
Xiao Si'r!
- Didn't you hear me calling?
- No.
The screen test is tomorrow.
Wanna come?
Sure.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
You seemed scared to see me.
You afraid
we'll be seen together?
Whoa, out on a date, huh?
Come on.
Let's not talk here.
- Let me have that porn.
- Here.
I thought your boyfriend wouldn't like it
if you took the screen test.
Is that why you're afraid
of being seen with me?
I just don't want any trouble.
I know Honey is your boyfriend.
You still won't admit
you're afraid of me?
You're funny.
What are you laughing at?
You're so honorable.
It'll get you in trouble.
Why?
Honey's like you.
Everyone's scared of him,
but they don't realize
he's straight as an arrow.
He can't stand things
that are unfair.
He takes it on himself
to straighten things out.
I tried to convince him
that he can't change
the world by himself.
He'd argue with me
and blame me
for discouraging him.
But now that he's gone,
I miss him so much.
I just cry and Cry-
I heard it was because of you
that Honey killed Redhead,
the former 217 boss,
and then went on the run.
Is that true?
Will you come watch
my screen test tomorrow?
If I come, I'll be up there.
You gonna do it?
There is a place
of peace and calm
Are you sure your weekly
Bible class and choir
won't affect
your grades at school?
Did you have a good time?
Careful!
Your father and I met
at a dance back in Shanghai.
We girls at the Teachers College
were very westernized.
Who'd have dreamed
I'd meet this peasant boy?
He'd just arrived in Shanghai
from Guangzhou.
Luckily Wang took him around
and showed him the real world.
He was a real peasant boy.
Lots of girls liked him,
and he didn't even know it.
I thought he was real special.
Sh.
Come with me.
What's the matter?
- Where's the watch?
- What watch?
Mom's watch.
Did Cat steal it?
Impossible!
I had it at lunchtime,
but tonight it was gone.
Wasn't he here this afternoon?
I took it.
What?
What got into you? Why?
I owe someone money.
Owe someone money?
How much?
- Four hundred.
You pawned it, didn't you?
I swear,
you'll be the end of me!
Mom will skin you alive
if she finds out!
How come you owed so much?
Threads took me to shoot pool
with the Village boys.
We lost big.
Now he's messing
with the Little Park boys.
I gotta get out clean
before all hell breaks loose.
Mom never wears
the watch anyway.
Here.
Go get the watch back.
I'll say I sent you
for some language books.
Be sure you bring one back.
Mrs. Fang!
Has she had asthma long?
She's had attacks before,
but never this serious.
Most asthma medication
is no longer effective on her.
She must be especially careful
when the weather changes.
Don't let her be
in unventilated places
or get too tired.
Isn't this your address?
They live with me.
It's that much?
Couldn't you give me
a little discount?
Her daughter said she knows you.
That's why I brought her here.
You've treated
her daughter before, right?
Well... yes.
But I can't make
decisions like this.
Are you thinking
about something sad?
Can you tell me about it?
Maybe you don't know
where to start.
Can you tel! me now?
Okay.
Not bad. Very good.
What now, sir?
Let's try a historical costume.
Are you sure?
All right.
Sir, the boss lady's here!
What's this I hear
about my leading lady?
The part calls for a teenager,
so we got a teenager.
Can you guarantee
the box office?
Well, times are hard...
It's very obvious.
You two made
the exact same mistakes.
I didn't lei him copy.
He just did.
Who are you trying to fool?
The exact same mistakes.
Not one word more
or one word less.
Demerits for both of you.
I made mistakes on purpose,
and he copied them.
You still dare to talk back?
I didn't do anything wrong.
You speak
to a teacher like that?
I didn't do anything wrong.
Keep talking back.
It'll get you another demerit!
Why?
Who's talking back
to a teacher like that?
You two again!
We have our regulations.
My hands are tied.
Try this new tea for a change.
He was obviously a victim,
and you're punishing him
without an investigation.
This isn't fair!
I send my son to you,
hoping he'll become
a decent, honest person.
If he makes mistakes,
I hope you'll correct him.
But when you act like this -
it's just not fair!
What is this? Lao Fan!
What the hell is this?
- What's the matter?
None of your business.
Your son's lucky.
The other boy's been expelled.
Because of all his demerits!
That's irrelevant!
You think your son
is a model student?
I've nabbed him myself
many times.
That has nothing
to do with this!
This isn't education!
You harass the good students!
Don't get excited.
We have our regulations.
There's no way I can help.
I'm not here for your help.
I'm here for justice.
I'm not looking for personal favors.
I don't need your help.
How can you have
such a bureaucratic attitude?
I can't believe it!
It's my fault.
I lost my cool.
It's a bad habit of mine.
I can't help it.
When I see these bureaucrats -
He deserved it.
But you really surprised me.
That's not what
you should be learning.
You might as well
take the demerit.
A person who'll apologize
for wrongs he didn't commit
is capable of all sorts
of terrible things.
But that kind of thing
seems to happen so often.
Exactly.
The purpose of education
is to search for the truth of life
to believe in.
If you can't be brave enough
to believe in it,
then what's the purpose of life?
Si'r, you're lucky.
I hope this incident
proves to be something positive
and not a setback.
You must believe that your future
is determined
by your own hard work.
You still unhappy?
About me getting you
this demerit?
No, I'm worried
about what Mom will think.
I'm worried for your sake.
Your poor mother.
All these years,
and she still worries about me.
Remember:
Things with a hole in the middle
bring headaches.
What's that mean?
Nothing. You'll find out
when you grow up.
What are you studying?
I'm studying at a cram school.
No, I mean the book.
It's so thick.
We all know
that your daughter goes
to the best college.
I didn't mean that.
Yeah, I'll bet.
But who cares where she goes?
My daughter doesn't go
running around with boys
and holding their hands.
Now, wait a second.
We're all neighbors.
Why that tone?
Exactly. I'm saying
this for your own good.
Don't get me wrong.
Kids nowadays
aren't what you think,
with their dating
and their street gangs.
Take him, for example,
at night school and all.
He must be tough to handle.
So a good school
isn't everything, is it?
Find something better to do
with your time!
So I don't have
a cushy job like yours.
I worked for the railroads,
you know!
And I quit myself!
No one fired me!
If you had better things
to do with your salary,
you wouldn't turn it over to me!
Without my credit, you'd starve!
What's gotten into you, Father?
You want another heart attack?
- You've been drinking again.
- Mind your own business!
When people negotiate,
they defuse the issue.
You end up getting him
a major demerit!
The demerit is beside the point.
He must learn
to be just and honorable.
This is the time
to insist on principles
and set a good example
for the children.
This isn't the time for principles!
I'm going to the bathroom.
- You always mess things up.
- Nonsense.
I've lived my life
at peace with myself.
I've never messed things up.
What's your problem?
I was reading.
Gimme!
Going out this late?
I need to borrow
a book from a friend.
Hurry home,
and don't be running around!
Mrs. Fang was kind to us.
My asthma's done it again.
I can't blame her
for letting me go.
Ming...
hurry and grow up.
My future depends on you.
Finally.
You kept us all waiting.
Get inside.
Move!
What are you staring at?
You got a problem?
Move!
Hurry UP-
It's okay.
They want you inside.
Come on in, Lao Er.
Take the bike for him.
You can't blame
Mrs. Fang for this.
You know my asthma condition.
Who knows when it'll act up?
Why make a big thing
about us moving back?
Things are different now.
Look at all these mouths
I have to feed.
You're the only relative we have.
Where else can we go?
You brought us to Taiwan
with your regiment.
If you don't want us,
send us away.
Why all the fuss?
I always move out
the minute I find work.
This place belongs to the army.
You're a freeloader here too.
A freeloader?
At her age, I was fighting
the Japs and the Commies!
Let me tell you:
I am this country.
This place belongs to the army,
so it's mine.
What a joke!
So we'll say you owe 350 of it.
I'm not responsible for it.
You're not? He says
he's not responsible for it.
What do you take us for?
I've been a little short
on cash recently.
Shandong,
you trust me, don't you?
Come this way. Do as I say.
Don't be a hothead like me.
Cool down a bit.
I heard...
your concert tickets
have been selling well.
Not at all.
Someone's trying to ruin it all.
Your concert
with the Little Park boys
has made us look bad.
You always share the goodies
with the other guys.
In this greasy little head of yours,
what are we really?
I'm gonna kick your ass
even if Shandong
lets you off easy.
Shit, the power again!
Threads, don't run off.
Stay where you are.
How could a jerk like Sly
have so much pull?
It's his old man who has
all the clout, not him.
What do you expect me to do?
I tell you what.
I'll give you a break
on the money you owe me.
Just do me one favor.
I want to meet with Sly.
Impossible! The two gangs
are bitter enemies.
Wheres the Independent News?
Orders from upstairs.
We only get the Central Daily now.
Going to the movies again?
What about school work?
Just play your game.
The days drag
since you got expelled, huh?
Shit.
What are you doing here?
I've becomes partners
with them in the concert.
Then I'm out.
Come on, don't be so rash.
Why let such a beautiful hall
sit vacant?
Look at it this way.
As long as the two of you
can work together,
there's no limit
to the bucks that'll roll in.
Think about it.
The whole 217 gang
will be behind you.
Who else will the Little Park boys
follow but you?
You want me
to betray my brothers.
Not a chance.
Make peace over a smoke.
Come on, have one.
Shit!
Now you're playing the Indian?
It seems you have...
woman problems.
Jade?
No problem there.
I'm not talking about Jade.
I've kept it under wraps...
or else we wouldn't
be here talking.
Right?
If you've got problems...
I can solve them for you.
Not that one.
The first song on side A.
Don't anyone move.
Which one of you is Tiger?
Won't show yourself, huh?
What a load of crap!
When can I get the lyrics?
- Depends on my big sister.
Tomorrow, okay?
- Still trying to hide?
- I'm not Tiger.
You're not, huh?
No!
It's not me!
Then who was the guy with Ming
at the shooting range?
Move it.
Did you get your kicks
fooling around
with one of our girls?
- Stand at attention!
- Attention!
Don't you know
how to stand at attention?
Where are you boys from?
Looking for trouble, fucker?
You know whose turf you're on?
It's Ma, General Ma's son.
Fuck you!
Where's your turf?
Wherever I am is my turf.
It was all a misunderstanding.
Okay, then it's all settled.
Let's get back to the village.
Thanks.
No problem.
Some of them recognized me.
I thought you were
a model student,
but you mess around with girls
and get into fights.
They picked a fight with me.
Getting in trouble over a girl
is just plain dumb.
Understand?
Where'd they go?
It's over.
What the hell's all this?
We came to save you.
You've actually used these
in fights? Shit!
You wanna fight?
Take this.
This is a real weapon.
Holy smokes! Cool, man!
Is this what you used
on that guy at Banqiao High?
Where'd you get it?
Right here, above the ceiling.
A Japanese general
used to live here.
Check your attic at home.
You might find something.
I found a bullet
for a Japanese rifle once.
Shit! What's this now?
A tape recorder from when
Eisenhower came here.
An American reporter left it
to my old man.
It can record a barking dog
ten miles away.
What are you doing, Cat?
Tearing the house apart?
I'm looking for rats.
You've moved back again.
They say every time you move,
you find a new boyfriend.
How about me this time?
Don't understand
what I'm saying?
You understand that, don't you?
You got some nerve,
moving back at a time like this.
We'll probably all end up
in trouble because of you.
Shit! Putting on
that “poor little me” look again?
Any word from Honey?
- Look who finally shows up!
- Did they call roll?
No, it was a study period.
What the hell's that?
Cat's record player.
Hey, can you get me
some tickets?
For the concert?
Ask Cat.
Neither he nor Airplane
showed up.
I'll ask him for you.
- Where do you come from?
- Hualien.
Hualien?
That's a nice place.
I was stationed there
for a month.
What made you come to Taipei?
There's a lot more
happening here.
You young people go
where the crowds are.
It's true,
a lot's happening in Taipei,
but nothing compared
to my hometown.
Take my hometown, for example.
I come from Qingdao.
Qingdao is -
A shot for your eyes?
I've run out. Try next week.
The architecture in Qingdao
is very special.
The Germans built it.
The drainage system
is remarkable,
with big wide canals.
It doesn't matter
how hard it rains.
Once it stops, there's never
any water on the ground.
Not like Taipei.
When it rains,
there's water everywhere.
Didn't you say you'd come
to my screen test?
Why didn't you show up?
Didn't you hear
I got a major demerit?
And remember when
some 217 guys saw you and me
at the shooting range?
They came after me
the other night at school.
I've had a string
of bad luck lately.
Cat told me to go
to the ice cream parlor.
He seemed nervous,
like something was up.
You saw Cat?
No wonder he and Airplane
cut class today.
I'll go with you.
I've got something for him.
Aren't you afraid of getting
into trouble again?
Nothing's going on between you and me.
What's to be afraid of?
- What are you doing here?
- Returning this to you.
The lyrics are inside.
- What are you doing here?
- You own the place?
It's cool, man.
He's here to see me.
You're acting gutsier
than last time I saw you.
I hear you two are having
a real sweet time lately.
Who are you talking about?
What an actor!
A real Gregory Pecker!
Now you're in deep shit.
Don't run off.
We're all brothers.
Forget it.
Tough guy, eh?
Where'd you learn it from?
Fuck! I'm gonna
teach you a lesson.
This doesn't hurt anymore, huh?
Just 'fishes, huh'?
Aren't you a model student?
How come you're getting angry?
He's not.
Want me to teach you
a lesson too?
Picking on a squirt like that -
pretty pathetic.
Come with me.
I was just taking care
of business for you.
- You look like a good kid.
- I'm here to see Cat.
You have no business here.
Get going.
You done talking?
Most of the guys
feel the same way.
Things can't go on
as they are now.
Someone has to take charge.
Things have to go on
when you're not here.
Your problems with
the 217 boys are personal.
They came for peace
on their own initiative.
The guys all think
we should consider it.
Think it over.
Let us know
what you think next time.
Shit!
This is open mutiny.
Brother.
Things aren't
as simple as you think.
Go tell Eastgate Ling
and Third-ring Ye
that I'm in town.
Tell them to come over.
Don't say anything else.
Shit.
Shandong and Threads have turned
the concert into quite an affair.
Let's add a little heat.
Does it have to be
during the concert?
Shit! No wonder you'll never be
a match for Sly.
All you worry about is
getting on stage and singing.
Am I right?
You're hopeless.
- Didn't you say Lao Er knows?
- About what?
What Threads
and the 217s are up to.
Lao Er.
Get up.
This is no time for talking.
Let's kill 'em!
Fuck! Why look for help
from Eastgate and Third-ring?
I've got enough guys
to do the job.
- What?
- Matches.
Shit, let's kill 'em!
How'd you get mixed up
with Threads?
I met him in a pool hall
near school
He said he knew
a way to make money.
The money sounded good, so -
I was only down south
a few months
before you guys here
started itching to make money.
Is life in Taipei really that hard?
Sly used to beg me
to take him into our gang.
If it weren't for you saying
his old man could let you use
the auditorium for your concerts,
I wouldn't give a shit
about that asshole.
Now that the 217 gang
is behind him,
he's showing his true colors.
All for a few bucks.
He's the boss of Little Park now,
understand?
Go tell Eastgate's
and Third-ring's boys
that we've decided
not to crash the concert.
Since both Shandong
and Threads know I'm back,
they'll take precautions.
I'll settle this score
some other time.
All right.
You going back
to Doggie's in Tainan?
You're welcome
to hide out here with us.
I'm going back to Tainan.
There's no future in hanging out
with these mainland kids.
I can speak Taiwanese
like you locals now.
I was like a mute in Tainan
not speaking the native language.
Thanks for all the hospitality.
Don't mention it.
A friend of Doggie's
is a friend of mine.
Deuce.
Go ahead and sing
at the concert.
It's no big deal.
Don't sweat it.
Relax and put on a good show.
You there.
Come over here.
Ming tells me
she likes you a lot.
I could tell right away
when I first met you.
Ming's been waiting
for you to get back.
When I got bored
while I was hiding out,
I'd read tons
of martial arts novels a day.
I'd tell them to get me
the thickest novels they could find.
I discovered people in the past
who were just like us street gangs.
There was this one guy.
Everyone thought he was crazy.
I remember...
everyone had run away...
and the city was set ablaze.
He alone stayed behind
to assassinate Napoleon.
In the end,
he failed and was caught.
War and Peace.
I've forgotten the names
of all the other novels.
That's the only one I remember.
Any problems?
No. Come and sit.
This is Horsecart.
Your name is...?
Xiao Si'r.
Ming will stay here a few days.
They know I'm in Taipei.
They'll put a tail on her.
She'll be very uncomfortable.
You know,
if you'd written back...
none of this
would have happened.
Shit!
If I could write,
I'd have written a novel!
For people like me
to read in the future.
It's too late now.
I didn't study hard enough.
Si'r, Sly's over there.
Just look at him. Shit!
Sly, let me introduce you
to a big shot.
Don't tag along everywhere!
Officer, this is the one
I told you about.
He's the manager's son.
What is it?
Who you tryin' to scare
with these cops from Juvenile?
I knew you were taking
precautions,
so I took my own.
You want to be responsible
if something happens?
Students.
We of course endorse
extracurricular activities like this.
But we must exercise restraint
as we have fun.
Trouble will only spoil it
for everyone.
Is that clear?
Yes, sir!
It's the national anthem!
Stand at attention, all of you!
Where's your ticket?
Who let you put on this concert?
You don't even consult me,
then you dare ask me
for a ticket?
Don't smoke when I'm talking!
Come on. I've been
through this number before.
Come on. I'll take you on.
Where's your boss?
Tell Shandong to come out.
I'll be right back.
Get your ass over here!
Distinguished guest...
please come in
and enjoy the music.
You're too kind.
I hear you want an agreement.
Here I am.
If you want an agreement,
talk to me first.
Hey, it's a happy day.
Let's talk things over
some other time.
There's nothing happy
between you and me.
If you've got the balls,
play for the money.
Who said you could have
this concert on my turf?
Fine. Come on and play.
Juvenile Division's inside.
Let's see you play now.
Think you're tough
'cause you outnumber me?
Come on.
All together now.
Or one at a time?
Let him go.
- Motherfucker!
- Hold it!
Let's talk out there.
This is how you 217 boys
always operate.
The Navy of the Republic! Shit!
I know that trick.
Chickenshits like him
put on uniforms to fool the cops.
I'll turn you in to the navy!
Autograph!
Sorry, folks!
This way, please.
You looking for someone?
No one's allowed backstage.
Just for a minute.
What'll it hurt?
Who the hell are you?
You're not on staff.
You really wanna know?
Okay, I'll give 'em a message.
It's private business.
No messages.
Cool it. Tell us who you want
and we'll send for him.
Airplane from Little Park.
So you get by because
you have lots of people, huh?
If you want to gang up on me
and kick my ass, fine.
This is between you and me.
Let's go over there.
I'm okay. Let him go!
That was for setting up
the concert behind my back.
Okay, let's start talking.
This is a peace talk.
You're all witnesses.
Come on.
Only two types of people
scare me, Shandong:
the type
that's not afraid to die,
and the type that has no shame.
Which type are you?
Not talking?
Don't wanna talk,
or afraid to talk?
You don't seem the type
that's not afraid to die.
I thought not.
You look so dark and dreary.
Don't be so unhappy.
What's there to be afraid of?
Put that away!
You lookin' for trouble?
Can't find him.
FUCK you!
Don't give me that shit.
Don't let me catch you alone.
What are you doing out here?
Get back inside.
Next time let me sing
an Elvis song, okay?
Shit! You singing Elvis!
Then I'll sing Connie Francis!
Take a look in the mirror!
You only pick
on your own people.
I'll show you I can.
Then start your own band.
Fine. I understand.
We doctors should show
a charitable spirit.
I told my father
about the medical expenses.
He understands
your financial situation.
There's no need to worry.
- Thank you.
- Don't mention it.
It appears her problem
is only partly physical.
Let her rest here a few days.
I'll take good care of her.
They all say Honey
was killed by the 217s,
but the newspapers say
it was a traffic accident.
Some people say he's AWOL
from the military.
Didn't he go back south?
Stop nagging!
It's none of your business!
Tell me. I made a bet
that the news was wrong.
How could he go AWOL?
Didn't you see it happen, Ma?
None of your fucking business!
Quit shooting off your mouth!
I'll beat the shit out of you.
Let's go. Time for class.
Already?
I've gotta go to the bathroom.
Why don't you go between classes?
I've been looking for you for days.
You didn't come to class.
Were you sick?
I thought he went back south.
Before leaving Taipei...
he left me the address
of his hideout.
I was planning to go see him.
He even laughed at me...
for being so worried.
It was strange.
For many days
while I lay sick in bed,
I couldn't recall Honey's face.
I was scared and confused.
Ming, don't be afraid!
You have to be brave!
I'm with you.
You needn't be afraid!
I'll always be with you!
I'll be your friend forever!
I'll protect you.
I don't need anyone's help.
No one can help anyway.
Hey, it's Ming! By herself.
- You got ideas?
- Shit! I wouldn't dare.
Hey, look.
Still blame me
for your leg injury?
- Wasn't Tiger going out with her?
- She's not talking to him.
Here he comes.
Weren't you going out with her?
Honey's dead.
Now she's anyone's game...
but I don't think
you stand much of a chance.
Honey's no problem,
dead or alive.
The idiot acted like
an arrogant prick at the concert.
He wasn't hit by no car.
The 217 boys let him have it.
You got something to say?
Goddamn it!
Hurry up
or I'll miss the last bus.
Take it easy.
I'll give you a ride.
Think I'll fall for that again?
Try Ihro wing I!
At me again, boy.
Look at this guy.
Is he for real?
I guess so.
Think it over.
Don't feel pressured.
I've got to go. it's late.
Getting Si'r transferred
to day school
is complicated.
I thought I could talk
my way through it
so he wouldn't have to take
the transfer exams.
I'll try my friends
on the Board of Education again.
Thanks a lot.
I'm still working
on your teaching certificate.
It'll take some time.
Good-bye.
How could he ask me
for a favor like that?
Try to just play along.
Don't be too hardheaded.
Don't let it get to you.
Try not to make enemies.
This isn't Shanghai,
where you had
Professor Hsia to back you up.
Being stubborn
won't make you any friends.
This time
it's the new office furniture.
Next time it'll be
the new building contract.
There'll be no end to it.
Haven't you figured him out yet?
You're the last person on his list.
God knows
how many others are involved.
What do you women know?
He must have his own problems.
I'll try to talk to him.
Are you crazy?
MING CAME TO SCHOOL TODAY, BUT...
Why'd you have to take him on?
Let's go find him.
We'll try the basketball court.
Shit! What's that?
- Follow me if you have the balls.
- It's suicide, man!
Suicide? I'll show them!
Take that!
And that!
It's useless.
This knife is for girls.
They'll laugh at you.
Where'd you get it?
In the attic,
with all the rest of it.
Cool it.
Stick to your tapes.
I've got an idea.
Let's get Ma's help.
Si'r, you guys are close.
Why ask other people for favors?
We gotta get revenge, damn it!
At least borrow
his samurai sword.
What's up?
That's what I want to know.
Cat said you wanted me.
No, I didn't.
Why the long face?
Is it a girl?
No.
I told you it wasn't that.
Getting worked up
over some chick looks bad.
Understand?
Look what happened to Honey.
Everyone on the street
was scared of him.
Then, all because
of some chick, he ends up -
Is it Tiger?
No.
That's good.
Load it.
Now hold on tight and aim up.
Go on.
Feels great, huh?
Unload and put in a new one.
Go over there, man.
Shit, I'm showing you
a good time!
Well?
Did you get a kiss out of her?
All this and not even a kiss?
She wouldn't let you?
Go on.
Take Jade around back.
Hurry UP-
She won't mind.
Shit! What is this?
I'm bending over backwards
for you, and you -
Forget it.
Dumplings and buns!
Si'r, where are you going?
Won't even answer!
Little punk!
Watch where you're going!
I love the night...
She's always nagging!
I can't stand her nagging!
Tough shit!
You again?
Working extra hours?
Making some money?
Every penny counts.
Why make so much?
Saving it for a wife?
Not one like yours.
You can't even drink at home.
What are you doing?
Don't act like a hooligan!
Don't come near me!
Sergeant Chad!
- What is it?
- Come quick!
Another heart attack.
Take it easy.
You sure are heavy.
I was afraid you'd have trouble
finding this place.
Xiao Si'r.
Let's kill Mao Zedong!
Skin Zhou Enlai!
Let's take back the mainland!
Horsecart!
How many vehicles you got?
- Plenty.
You gotta be careful.
You trust the drivers?
- They're all our people.
Good.
Who's that kid?
- He's with me.
Why'd you turn it off?
I didn't.
It took forever to tune.
Now I have to start all over.
Why'd you use my comic books?
I looked all over for them.
You know how long
it takes to tune this?
Go get it fixed, will you?
LITTLE PARK ICE CREAM PARLOR
What are you doing?
- Damn you, Blind Man!
- Goddamn it!
Go to hell!
Selfish bastard!
You took advantage of me!
Take your records with you!
I don't want them!
You'll be sorry when I'm dead!
You no-good,
shameless bastard!
Any woman
who touches you is cursed!
Cheat! Asshole!
You're not a man!
You picked a great time
to join the gang -
the night of a typhoon!
Even Baldy hasn't shown up.
Ka Wu's gone to get him.
Why so jittery?
Where you going?
To take a shit.
Don't cut out on us.
The typhoon's coming.
Why haven't you closed up?
Useless old motherfucker.
Go home and jerk off!
FUCK you!
Relax.
The power's out.
How come no one's around?
You two go watch the back door.
What do we do about this guy?
Can we go back now?
Put that cleaver down!
You all right?
Go after them!
The initiation's starting
and you're home asleep!
- It was mahjong.
- Mahjong my ass!
You still owe me from last time,
remember?
Let's play another game
afterwards.
Ka Wu!
Do you know
how lonely life can be?
You know what it feels like
in the depths of despair?
Then go kill yourself!
You're a fuckin' drag.
No one respects me.
What's the use of living?
I'm better off dead.
Please let me borrow that.
Help me -
Run!
Crazy...
Did you kill Honey?
Shandong!
Crazy...
Please get up!
Come on, get up.
Shandong!
I could swear he sings
“...a brighter summer day.”
But is that grammatically correct?
Mr. Zhang.
What is it?
Could we do this tomorrow
during office hours?
It's a rather unusual matter...
All right.
Let me get a jacket.
Is it something Si'r did?
Residents in southwest Taiwan
should be prepared for floods.
People on ships
in the vicinity of Taiwan
should also be on the alert...
You go to bed.
I'll wait up for Mom.
Mom went to Mr. Wang's house.
She's been gone two hours.
People came and took Dad away.
I think they were
with the Secret Police.
You're soaking wet!
- I forgot my raincoat.
You seem to lack inner calm.
Don't give me your religion.
I've lived an honest life.
I have nothing to hide.
We have no doubt of that.
May I go, then?
I have to go to work.
You'd better rest a bit first.
Is this about
Professor Hsia again?
We only touched
on one element last night.
Here.
Relax.
Write what you feel.
Don't hold back.
I studied music.
I'm an artistic type.
You're really my superior
in that regard.
I really do understand
how educated people feel.
Well, I'll leave you alone
for a while.
Oh, one other thing.
There's no actual sign,
but smoking's not allowed.
Sorry. It's the rules.
But before -
The blood and tears
I shed for you know no end
As I cast aside the red bean
symbol of my longing
The spring willows
bloom eternally
And spring flowers
fill my painted chambers
My sleep's disturbed
by the wind and rain
Pattering on the screen window
after dusk
I'm unable to forget my new woes
Or my old sorrows
I can't swallow my delicate foods
And I choke
on the golden brasenia soup
I can't believe
How frail I look
in my flowered mirror
I can't unfurrow my knitted brow
Nor bear to feel
another tear fall
Do you know Li Nan-tien?
Uh... yes.
College classmate.
So why didn't you write it down?
He didn't come to Taiwan.
We've lost contact.
Didn't come to Taiwan?
You know Liang Jin-chen?
Liang Jin-chen?
I don't think
I've heard the name before.
Think carefully. Are you sure?
I don 7 think so.
Think carefully.
In July 1939 you began work
in an accounting department.
Who trained you
to take over his job?
Oh... Mr. Liang.
A sort, chubby guy
with gold-rimmed glasses.
So you do remember.
Why didn't you write it down?
I wasn't lying.
We work so hard
to learn the truth.
Leaving out something you know
is the same as lying.
You know Chao Nien-lu?
- No.
Hsun Feng-shih?
Kuo Li-an?
Yes.
Shih Chun-chuan?
How do you know him?
He was a friend of a coworker.
When we first came to Taiwan,
I bought an old bike
from him real cheap
so the kids could get to school.
I only met him once.
A reporter or something.
His name was kind of odd.
That's why I remember it.
Is that all?
Yes.
Why didn't you write it down?
Who was the coworker?
Mr. Tseng.
Tseng Hung-yuan.
- How do you write that?
“Hung” as in “swan.”
You and your wife married secretly
in Shanghai in 1940.
We had witnesses
and a dinner-
Without a marriage certificate,
it's a secret marriage.
We registered at city hall,
and we -
Did Professor Hsia
introduce you to your wife?
No, we met at a dance.
In June of 1942, your wife
was teaching elementary school.
Why did she resign?
My eldest daughter was born.
My salary was enough
at the time.
I preferred to have her
care for the baby.
Is that the only reason?
This says she left for her uncle's
in Shanghai at age 11.
Shouldn't it say
her father's brother-in-law?
Well, I -
You seem to lack inspiration.
There's much
you still don't recall.
Don't worry. We have
all the time in the world.
You grow so fast.
Hold your breath.
Remind me to let it out
for you tonight.
What happened with your old man?
What do you mean?
That night after the fight, did he notice
anything when you got home?
No, he'd gone to a movie
with my mom.
Wow, your sister's really cool!
Thanks.
Move.
I found that picture
with the knife.
She must have used it
in a love suicide.
Quit staring at it.
Take it if you want.
Hey, I talked to Horsecart!
- What for?
I told him I'm your buddy.
He'll help us.
Stand up straight.
Don't make me repeat myself.
You got that?
There's no one here.
I knew you'd be here.
What you told me last time...
did you really mean it?
I hope you weren't lying.
I couldn't bear that.
It's Saturday again.
Want to cut class?
No, we have all the time
in the world.
Spring disappears
Without a trace
Leaving nothing behind...
Here for your shot?
Go over there.
Apologize to them.
Go on!
Want me to make you?
Motherfucker!
Is that good enough?
Forget it. Let's go.
Not a chance!
Just watch your step
from now on.
What are you so pleased about?
Fix me up with Airplane!
Cat is cuter.
I want to meet Airplane!
I want one too!
You need to be
more aggressive on defense.
Don't let him get by.
Next two.
Keep your arms out on defense.
Go on.
What's your connection
to Wang Kuo-cheng?
Wang?
He's...
a classmate.
“Wang”?
You seem to know him well.
Well... not really.
I see him now and then
at class reunions.
Here.
Write more?
I'll be back for it before dawn.
I'm almost done.
Give me a little more time.
That's enough.
You can go now.
Hurry UP-
- Hurry up.
- My button fell off again.
- Didn't your sister just fix it for you?
- Yes.
Mrs. Zhang.
Do you have safety pins?
You better go or you'll be late.
Is my shirt ironed?
I have to go to work.
It's better this way.
They found someone at the office
to take over my work.
Less work means less trouble.
You think it's related
to your interrogation?
Don't say things with no proof.
How stupid can you be?
Weren't they waiting for a confession
about Wang before they'd release you?
I thought
he was trying to help us.
The way I see it...
he was trying
to dissociate himself from you.
You're too honest
to cover up his corruption.
What kind of crazy idea is that?
Didn't you go to him
while I was being held?
Didn't he do his best to help?
Maybe he was pretending.
Maybe he was behind the whole thing.
And that promotion he got you -
You women!
You know nothing
about friendship between men!
What are you good for
besides being suspicious?
It's been tough enough
for us already.
You and the kids
are all I have left.
Please don't frighten me anymore.
We only have each other now.
If you're not afraid,
then I won't be.
What's the matter, Tiger?
Come on, speak up.
You should at least talk to him.
You worried
he'll try to get back at you?
He won't.
It's over.
Let's drop him, okay?
How come you never
told me about him?
What's there to tell?
Lots of guys have ideas about me.
Haven't you heard enough?
Take the young doctor,
for example.
Couldn't you tell?
How do you feel
when I tell you these things?
Can't you just ignore them?
You can't ask others to do
what you think is right.
People will look down on you.
You mean you'll look down on me.
Who's there?
Lao Er, Si'r, get up!
There's a thief!
Lao Er, get up, hurry!
Lao Er!
See if the front door's
been opened. Hurry!
The front door's fine.
You sure?
Yes.
Take this!
He's hiding.
He's hiding outside.
Impossible!
Check the roof!
- Get the flashlight.
- Where is it?
Hurry!
- In the kitchen drawer. Hurry!
I can't find it.
Why don't you turn on some lights?
What's with all the noise?
I'm trying to sleep!
He's hiding under the bed.
He was standing right here
and then suddenly vanished!
It can't be!
I saw him right here!
How could he just vanish?
He couldn't have gotten away!
Let her rest for now.
Everything's under control.
Luckily you rushed her over
in time.
Didn't I warn her
about charcoal smoke?
Since ancient times
the Chinese have loved camellias
for their elegance
and refined beauty.
The kids used
to play around here
and pick the flowers
when they were little.
This reminds me
of your grandfather.
The blossoms bring back
happy memories of him.
Who's that lady?
You mean Hsiang-Ii?
We're getting married
in September.
I don't like her.
She's strange.
There's no love between you.
She's not for you.
You kids don't understand
such things.
You don't have to say anything
if you don't want to.
Why do you think
I don't understand?
Love isn't fun and games.
Lots of guys say they love me,
but...
the minute there's trouble,
they all run away.
If you're troubled about something,
you must tell me
before I can help you.
I won't tell you.
You wouldn't tell me, right?
Don't worry about
your mother's medical expenses.
We're too close
to worry about such things.
Still don't want to tell me?
Zhang Zhen.
Come here a minute.
This is for your own good.
I don't mean to pry,
but for a love affair at your age,
you need good advice.
Behaving like a hooligan, huh?
Stand up straight
when the doctor's talking!
Motherfucking bitch.
What are you?
The secret police?
What did you just say?
Say that again.
What did you say?
I said you're the secret police.
Before that.
About my mother.
Try saying it again!
- Fucking bitch!
What's going on?
What's this here?
Your students act
like a bunch of hooligans.
Foul-mouthed and violent!
Dating girls and messing around
with relationships!
- Mind your own fucking business!
- Zhang Zhen!
To the conduct office!
Big deal! Who cares?
You had some harsh words
about us last time.
What about
your parental guidance?
Such foul language!
Even I was embarrassed.
You parents don't do your job
and then blame it on us.
You have some nerve!
Please give him another chance.
Too late!
He's fallen this far already.
If we don't punish him properly,
you'll blame us again
for not doing our job.
I don't want to be
responsible for that.
It was my negligence.
Kids sometimes lose their heads.
Please excuse him just this once.
If he gets
another demerit for this,
he can't move on
to the next grade.
That would be...
too unfair to him.
Unfair? Didn't you think
we were unfair last time?
Didn't you say
you didn't care about demerits?
How come you care now?
We all work
for the same government.
What makes you
so high and mighty?
Mr. Zhang, buy some buns!
What's wrong?
In a bad mood?
Don't worry!
The sun will rise again tomorrow.
A lively soul is never
stifled by a fart, right?
Dumplings and buns!
Don't worry, Dad.
Getting expelled isn't that bad.
This way I can take
the transfer exam this summer.
I'll get into day school for you.
Don't worry about me, Dad.
I remember everything you said.
I'll always listen to you.
I remember you said
one's own future
can be determined
by one's own efforts.
I hit him with the bat
because he went too far,
just like last time when you -
If I quit smoking,
the money I save every month...
will be enough
to buy you glasses
on the installment plan.
So when will we see
each other again?
Not until I've taken
the transfer exams.
You can always come
to school to see me.
Next time I enter the school gate,
I'll be a day school student.
Sounds like Honey when he said
he was going back to Tainan.
You're not happy.
I'll be worried about you.
Don't be silly. Study hard.
I'm behind you all the way.
But let's not go today, okay?
Everything's all arranged.
Plus Cat and Airplane
are both invited.
Oh, dear!
Our servant has quit.
Sorry I didn't come out
earlier to say hello.
Don't worry.
We'll help ourselves.
Is this your classmate?
She's so pretty.
When I was carrying him,
I wanted a girl.
Look how big he is now.
There you go again!
Take your feet off the table.
Where are the others?
- Range?
- 700 yards.
- How many?
- A platoon.
Too far. It won't reach.
Use mine.
Shit! They've got tanks!
It's okay.
We've got grenades.
Who goes there? Password!
Commie woman.
Hands up.
- What are you doing?
- Girls aren't into this stuff.
Stay back!
Cheer up, will you?
Doesn't my thoughtfulness
mean anything?
Getting expelled from school
is no big deal.
You don't even look
after your own girlfriend.
Your father's government career
is doomed because of it
and because of his relations
with Professor Hsia.
I'm proud of all you kids
for pulling through.
Especially Si'r.
He's so determined to get back
on track after all that's happened.
Mom, after graduation,
I'll work a while before going abroad.
No, you go as soon as you get
your scholarship.
But Lao Er's going to college,
plus there's Si'r and the youngest one.
It's too much for you.
We've managed up to now.
Don't worry until
you've made it in America.
Four pounds of rice.
Can you put this on credit,
Uncle Fat?
No problem.
May I butt in?
Many people say I'm too nosy,
but I'm actually
a lot like your husband.
You have preserved eggs?
Over there.
Your SH saved my “fie.
I think it's my turn to help you.
Uncle Fat said Mr. Lin
is native Taiwanese.
A very honest man.
He's starting
a fruit export business.
He needs a partner
with formal education.
The starting salary
may not be much,
but if you work hard,
you'll be your own man.
What if he goes bankrupt
a month from now?
Talk to him first.
Feel each other out.
You can't doubt a guy
without knowing him.
I've worked
for the government all my life.
I'm used
to the stability and security.
You really think
this is stable and secure?
I was gonna mail it today
if you didn't show up.
Did you bring your friend
some slippers, Cat?
What did I go out there for?
Why'd you turn it off?
It sounds awful!
Who are you mailing it to?
You'll find out later.
How's school?
Everything okay?
Same as always.
Nothing ever changes.
You seen Ming lately?
She's fine!
Just concentrate on your books.
Me and Airplane
will look after her.
Chiung, come give me a hand.
Uncle Fat's family
will be here at 7:00.
Clear the table, would you?
Where's Sh'?
I sent him to the movies.
“The score with Sly
will be settled by this day.”
Sly?
He hasn't come around in ages.
He disappeared
after he escaped the massacre.
They fired his old man
because of him.
They hold political meetings
in the auditorium,
but outsiders
can't rent it anymore.
I got the worst of it.
My business has gone to hell.
The damn cops
come round all the time.
Closing up already?
Shit! Look who's here!
Sh.
Jade said she's been
seeing you at the library.
You got kicked
out of school too?
You seem really different.
Move your feet.
I was really too much back then...
wound up so tight all the time.
It makes me laugh!
Don't let the past
get you down, okay?
I feel really bad about it.
Come on, man.
It was all my fault.
Let it go.
What school
are you trying to get into?
I'm trying to test
into day school.
You got some balls!
Even military academies
won't take punks like me.
You and I were such enemies.
Now we're in the same boat.
We even have the same
bad luck with girlfriends.
What do you mean?
That Ma!
He's really slick.
I figure you'll be like me
and not hold it against him.
He stole Jade from me.
Now he's messing around
with Ming.
When are you signing up
for the exams?
My math and English
are the pits -
Sh.
Let's keep in touch.
What was that for?
You want trouble, asshole?
Mess with me
and I'll call the cops!
Motherfucker!
- Come on, forget it.
- Who are you here to see?
- Is Ma home?
Wait here.
What's your name?
Si 'r.
Shit, it's been a long time!
What have you been up to?
That's what I want to ask you.
I'm the same old me.
What else?
Hey, did you know
Ming's living here now?
Remember when you guys came over
and our maid had quit?
Ming came to my mom to see
if her mother could fill the job.
My mom really likes her
and gave her mother the job.
Ming's not bad.
She's inside.
Want to come in?
What's this I hear
about you and her?
What do you mean?
Girls. It's the same old shit.
Dress 'em nice, feed 'em well,
fool around a bit.
What else is there?
You don't look too happy.
Don't let some stupid girl
come between us, buddy.
It's okay.
When you two were fooling around,
did she mention Honey a lot...
and say you weren't giving her
a sense of security?
What's wrong? Don't get
all worked up over some girl!
Come on in.
Let's shoot a few rounds.
That's okay.
I'm gonna catch a movie.
- Got any money on you?
- A little.
How much?
How much you need?
Never mind.
Look at it
as meeting friends for dinner.
Just be relaxed.
Chuan, I need my watch.
I put it back.
Well, it's not here.
Uncle Fat's here.
- I want to go.
- I'll bring you bubble gum.
Lousy bubble gum!
How many for dinner?
Si'r is studying at the library.
How about Lao Er?
I don't know.
He's had a good appetite lately.
What's wrong?
You're always outside
whenever Mom's gone.
Come eat your dinner!
I'm not hungry yet.
- You're asking for it!
- I'm coming.
- Is stealing Mom's watch a habit now?
- I didn't take it.
She noticed it was gone!
What will you do now?
What's this about?
It's for grown-ups.
Stay out of it.
You're so mean!
Where are you going?
- Are your folks home?
- They went out to dinner.
- What's with Lao Er?
- Oh, nothing.
It's been ages.
Are they doing all right?
I'll come in a while and wait.
Where are all the ashtrays?
Dad quit smoking.
You still using this thing?
It's useless!
You know, I took your dad
to buy this radio.
At the Wing On
department store in Shanghai.
Your mom wasn't even
as old as you are now.
You should throw
that useless junk away.
What were you doing
at the church library?
My sister told me about it.
How about you?
I play when it's time to play,
study when it's time to study.
So Chiung is your sister?
She's really religious.
We were both
in the church choir at one point.
What'll we do after the movie?
- Some rock and roll joint?
No, too expensive.
You want to be like Ma?
Don't be stupid.
Didn't you quit?
How about 300 a game?
Shit!
You need money that bad?
This is a real opportunity for you.
I was impressed with Mr. Lin.
He's honest and direct.
It's time to stop
dragging your feet.
Dad, Mr. Wang was here.
I forgot your bubble gum!
I'll make it up to you next time.
Why the sad face?
- Big sister bawled me out.
She did?
Were you naughty?
No.
Then why'd she do that?
- Where's Lao Er?
- He went out.
Where'd he go?
Little brat!
Just had to snitch, didn't you!
I saw Sly last night.
He's totally changed.
I guess people really do change.
It was a comforting feeling.
What are you going on about?
Jade, can we be close
to each other?
I could help you feel
that same way.
Don't you need that sometimes?
You're a serious one,
aren't you?
Didn't you look down
on me before?
Actually -
Now you seem eager to change me.
Am I your little
biology experiment, or what?
You have a lot
of philosophical ideas.
I'm happy with the way I am,
but are you?
What if I don't change?
What if I don't change
to suit your ideas?
Will you just walk away?
You're so selfish!
Who do you think you are?
Jade, I didn't mean any harm.
By the way, thanks for the rumors
you started back then.
What rumors? Back when?
Playing dumb?
When the 217 boys
cornered Sly at the school.
Did you really not see
it was Ming he was with?
Sly was scared
Honey might find out.
He made me tell everyone
it was me.
I was such an idiot!
Why don't you give Ming
your philosophy lecture?
She's got me beat by a mile.
You're shameless!
Hopeless!
Tell your father you're sorry.
That's enough, Dad.
That's enough!
Dad, please stop!
Please stop!
You better come back later.
Mom and Dad think
you're studying at the library.
If they find out
you took the watch...
they'll be even more heartbroken.
Lao Er came up
with a load of cash.
He wanted to buy back
the watch for you...
but Mom found
the money on him first.
You mustn't feel alone.
I'm always with you.
Don't turn me away again.
Let God into your heart.
He'll give you his strength.
But...
there's too much suffering...
too much injustice.
Aren't you giving others
too little credit
and always thinking
only of yourself?
Christ gave his life
for our sins.
Even Lao Er took the blame
for your wrongs.
You should show gratitude
for what others have done for you.
Have you ever done
anything for anyone?
You should think it over carefully.
Honey told me the same thing.
Who?
Never mind.
A good friend.
Have you ever read
War and Peace ?
Why don't you talk it over
with Reverend Chen tomorrow?
- What's up?
- We're not finished yet.
- What's this about?
- Don't play dumb, asshole.
Fuck you, going off on me
over some girl!
Aren't you my bUddY?
You go on like an old lady.
You said you'd given up
girls for books.
Now you start bitching.
You got some nerve!
I've always been good to you.
- Shut your mouth!
Shut your mouth and listen good.
I've had enough
of your rich-kid theories.
Starting today...
if I hear you're still
hanging out with Ming,
I'm coming after you!
Motherfuckin' punk!
I let you be my best friend!
Fuck! Don't forget
who you're messing with!
I'll be waitin' for you, buddy!
I'll kick your ass!
I've been looking all over for you.
Cool it. We're all good friends.
Cool it for my sake, okay?
Let's talk it over.
I'll bring him to you.
Come on, man.
Don't act this way.
It makes us look bad.
Wait at the film studio.
I'll go talk to him.
I'll bring him to you.
Cool it for my sake.
Come on, man.
Let's drop it for today.
I need time to talk to him.
He brought
his samurai sword to class.
Let's do it tomorrow, okay?
Go home and cool down.
Do it for me, okay?
Let's make it tomorrow, okay?
Okay? For sure?
I gotta go.
I'm late for class.
Your brother's not here yet?
My family said he was on his way.
Well...
let's wait another half hour.
- I'm sorry, Reverend Chen.
- It's okay.
Well... excuse me.
Hey there!
Can you help me find
that young girl you were with before?
She moved after the screen test.
You know where to?
She cries and laughs,
and makes it all look natural!
Natural?
You can't even tell real from fake.
How can you make movies?
You even know
what the hell you're filming?
Cat's at school.
I'm just borro wing a book.
What book?
I know where it is.
How come his bike's still here?
Strange. He's usually
the first one out of here.
Si?!
What's the matter?
What brings you here to school?
What's that?
Stop acting like this.
You're here for Ma.
Tell me! Are you?
How could you do
a thing like that?
I won't let anyone
look down on you.
What are you talking about?
Aren't you supposed
to be home studying?
Ming, I know all about you.
But I don't mind.
Because only I know.
I'm the only one
who can help you.
I'm the only hope you have left.
Just like Honey used to be.
That's why
you still can't forget Honey.
Because right now,
I'm another Honey.
You mean you're the only one
who can help change me, right?
Why are you like all the rest?
I was wrong about you.
You're just like the others.
You're nice to me
just so I'll be nice to you.
Then you'll feel secure, right?
You're so selfish.
You want to change me?
I'm like this world.
This world will never change!
Who do you think -
You're hopeless!
Shameless and hopeless!
Ming.
Get up.
Quick, get up.
Get on your feet.
You won't die. Believe me.
Hurry and get UP-
You can do it.
Please get up.
Get up!
Why won't you get UP?
Where is he?
I'm looking for my brother.
You got the wrong person!
You've made a mistake!
Where's Sh'?
So that's the guy.
Strange.
I don't know this one.
What gang is he with?
I know every one
of these assholes in town.
“Dear Sis...”
Found that in his pocket.
“I'm sorry.
I know you're the only one
who understands.
Please help explain
to Mom and Dad...
in case I never see you again.”
What's the little jerk's name?
Can't even write his name.
Drew a funny face!
What's his problem?
XIAO SFR
Get up.
Time to change.
Get up and get changed!
You little punk!
She's mine!
You can't take her away!
You can't do this!
It belongs to my old man.
Ask him where he got it.
I didn't ask him!
I'm asking you!
Why'd you bring
this sword to class?
I know
you're mixed up in all this!
We know your father well.
Can't you just cooperate?
That's my son!
What are you doing to him?
This is outrageous!
We're a respectable family!
Treating an innocent child
like this!
The latest report:
The girl's mother
just committed suicide.
Who's in charge here?
I am! I'm the boss here!
Now you get out!
- How dare you speak to me like that!
- Out!
Who is that man?
I want his name!
What's his name?
Write down his name!
He was the only friend I had.
And now...
We heard the girl's mother
tried to kill herself.
Tell us about it.
Let us talk to her.
Everyone wants to know
what really happened.
She tried to kill herself
by swallowing her gold ring.
I really don 'I know much else.
Please be considerate.
Do you know the boy?
Relax. The mother survived.
No big deal.
I heard you had
an affair with the girl.
Any comment?
- We heard the same thing.
What?
Have you no decency?
Get out! All of you!
Who do you think you are?
Out!
He has a guilty conscience.
What's wrong
with asking a question?
Let's check out
the police department again.
There is a place
of peace and calm
Safe in G0d's embrace
In that place
No evil dwells
Safe in G0d's embrace
Jesus, our benevolent savior
Comes from G0d's embrace
We earnestly await the time
When we'll rest in G0d's embrace
In the summer of 1961,
Xiao Si'r received
the death sentence
from the District Court of Taipei.
Being the first juvenile
homicide case in Taiwan
under Nationalist
government rule,
the case and sentence
were widely debated.
The District High Court
later commuted the sentence
to 15 years in prison.
Xiao Si'r was released from prison
shortly before his 30th birthday.
Two months after the incident...
The other gentlemen said
you accept tapes.
Who said that?
You're making it up.
We never accept tapes.
I wanted to leave a letter.
He said letters get lost easily
in the mail room.
He suggested a tape instead.
- Are you a family member?
- No.
Mister, didn't you say
you accept tapes?
Do you or don't you?
- Who's it for?
- Zhang Zhen.
All right.
Just leave it and go!
Si'r, remember
this song I recorded?
Guess who I mailed it to.
Elvis!
He even wrote back.
He was surprised to learn
his music is so popular
on this unknown little island.
He was touched.
He even sent me a gift.
Too bad you can't see it.
I wear the ring
he sent me every day.
It's really cool!
I just don't know
when I 'II get to show it to you.
What's this thing?
Shit!
Hey, the radio's working!
Don't move it!
It'll cut out again!
Kang Fu-mei,
Wang Chao-jen, Yeh Hsin-ming...
Chao Hung,
Chen Cheng-chen...
The preceding have qualified
for the Chinese Literature Department.
The following have qualified
for the Foreign Literature Department
at National Taiwan University:
Chou Fu-jung, Chang Shih-ling...
Chen Cheng-fu, Chang Chih-ho...
Also Featuring
WANG CHUAN, CHANG HAN
CHIANG HSIU-CHIUNG
STEPHANIE LAI
WONG CHI-ZAN, LAWRENCE KO
TAN CHIH-KANG
CHANG MING-HSIN, JUNG CHUN-LUNG
ZHOU HUI-GUO
TANG HSIAO-TSUI, LIN HONG-MING
BOSEN WANG
CHEN HUNG-YU
HSU MING, CHO MING
Set Decoration by EDWARD YANG
Production Design by
YU WEI-YEN
Costume Design by
WU LE-CHIN